U.S. President's Railroad Commission Photographs 5003 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series XXXII: Union Pacific Railroad: Denver Union Terminal and Freight Houses
  - Rocky Mountain Warehouse Alley and Hassco Spur, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 91)
    Buildings in center background are on Wyncoop Street between 18th and 19th Streets. 19th street runs between the tine building and buildings in foreground. The next two tracks to the right are known as Tri-way 1 and 2. The fourth track is known as Nobles Spur; the fifth is the middle track for Hendrie & Bolthoff,and the sixth serves the Beatrice Food Company. Extensive foot, truck, and automobile traffic in this area. In right of photo is the UP freight house, dock, and offices. There are very close clearances and heavy truck and pedestrian traffic in this alley.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 63, Folder 91)
  - Denver Union Terminal Tracks, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 97)
    Short train shed between tracks No. 10 and No. 11. To the left are the CB&Q team tracks and industrial area. Cars, engines, and automobiles park very close to tracks.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 63, Folder 97)
- Series XXXIII: Union Pacific Railroad: Pocatello, Idaho passenger depot and freight yards
  This series consists of photographs of the Union Pacific's facilities in Pocatello, Idaho and surrounding areas. The UP is a freight hauling railroad that operates 8,500 locomotives over 32,100 route-miles in 23 states west of Chicago and New Orleans. The Union Pacific Railroad system is the largest in the United States and it is one of the world's largest transportation companies. These photographs were not submitted to the Commission and as such do not have identifying exhibit numbers and the inclusion of some photographs in this series is tentative. Of interest in this series is the photographs of Union Pacific locomotives and rolling stock, the photographs of the Pocatello Passenger Depot, and documentation of the streets and industries in and around Pocatello.
  - Industrial Siding with Grade Crossing, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 191)
    "McLaughlin for Senator" sign.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 191)
  - Yard Engine in Locomotive and Freight Classification Yard (Box 60, Folder 32)
    "Road of the Streamliner" on unit
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 60, Folder 32)
  - Freight Cars and Tank Cars on Tracks with Yard Engines (Box 62, Folder 58)
    Union Pacific Units. UP Unit 1079.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 58)
  - Freight Classification Yard (Box 62, Folder 59)
    Union Pacific Unit 1079
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 59)
  - Railroad Crossovers and Tank Cars (Box 62, Folder 60)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 60)
  - Freight Cars on Tracks and Industries on Right (Box 62, Folder 61)
    Ice dock on left side of photograph.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 61)
  - Freight Cars on Crossover Tracks and Industries on Right (Box 62, Folder 62)
    Ice dock in left side of photograph.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 62)
  - Yard Engine in Locomotive and Freight Classification Yard (Box 62, Folder 63)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 63)
  - Freight Classification Yard (Box 62, Folder 64)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 64)
  - Railroad Yard with Close Clearance (Box 62, Folder 65)
    "Danger Impaired Clearance" sign. Locomotive in right of photograph.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 65)
  - Cars on Railroad Track and Freight Cars in Background (Box 62, Folder 66)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 66)
  - Freight Classification Yard (Box 62, Folder 67)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 67)
  - Freight Classification Yard (Box 62, Folder 68)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 68)
  - Railroad Track Crossover and Freight Cars (Box 62, Folder 69)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 69)
  - Grade Crossing and Freight Cars (Box 62, Folder 70)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 70)
  - Freight Yard (Box 62, Folder 71)
    Ice dock in center-left of photograph.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 71)
  - Railroad Crossovers and Industry (Box 62, Folder 72)
    "Rocky Mountain Gas, Phone 856"
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 72)
  - Railroad Crossovers and Industry (Box 62, Folder 73)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 73)
  - Freight Cars Next to Loading Platform (Box 62, Folder 74)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 74)
  - Railroad Track Crossovers, Freight Cars and Tank Cars (Box 62, Folder 75)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 75)
  - Loading Platform and Freight Cars (Box 62, Folder 76)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 76)
  - Industrial Siding (Box 62, Folder 77)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 77)
  - Industrial Siding (Box 62, Folder 78)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 78)
  - Industrial Siding (Box 62, Folder 79)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 79)
  - Union Pacific Locomotive Unit No. 1082 (Box 62, Folder 80)
    Union Pacific Unit #1082, Baldwin VO 1000
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 80)
  - Cabooses and Freight Cars (Box 62, Folder 81)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 81)
  - Freight Cars Next to Loading Platform (Box 62, Folder 82)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 82)
  - Multi Track Loading and Unloading Platforms (Box 62, Folder 83)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 83)
  - Freight Cars Next to Loading Platforms (Box 62, Folder 84)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 84)
  - Intersection of Route 30 and Route 91/191 (Box 62, Folder 85)
    Grade crossing at busy intersection
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 85)
  - Intersection of Route 30 and Route 91/191 (Box 62, Folder 86)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 86)
  - Intersection of Route 30 and Route 91/191 (Box 62, Folder 87)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 87)
  - Union Pacific Locomotive 1499 (Box 62, Folder 88)
    GP7 in front, FP7 behind.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 88)
  - Car Shops (Box 62, Folder 89)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 89)
  - Industry Siding and Yard (Box 62, Folder 90)
    Mostly freight cars and cabooses in yard
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 90)
  - Union Pacific Locomotive X-20 (Box 62, Folder 91)
    GE 8500 GTEL B Unit and Tender
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 91)
  - Union Pacific Locomotive X-20 (Box 62, Folder 92)
    Tender and Back Half of B Unit
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 92)
  - Union Pacific Passenger Depot (Box 62, Folder 93)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 93)
  - Union Pacific Locomotives Nos. x1454, 510 and 273 or (279) F3A F3B, F9A & F9B, GP9 (Box 62, Folder 94)
    1454: F3A & F3B, 510 (in background): F9A & F9B, 273/(279): GP9.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 94)
  - Freight Cars Under Platform Attached to Industry (Box 62, Folder 95)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 95)
  - Rear End of Tender of Union Pacific Locomotive X-20, Locomotive to Left is SD 24 B-L (Box 62, Folder 96)
    Union Pacific 21; Union Pacific 400 B
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 96)
  - Railroad Tracks Leading to Freight Yard and Passenger Depot (Box 62, Folder 97)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 97)
  - Tracks Leading to Freight Yard and Pocatello Passenger Depot (Box 62, Folder 98)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 98)
  - Railroad Track Crossovers Alongside Tank Cars and Freight Cars (Box 62, Folder 99)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 99)
  - Union Pacific Passenger Cars on Tracks (Box 62, Folder 100)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 62, Folder 100)
  - Union Pacific Locomotive Unit 426 (Box 63, Folder 169)
    Manufacturer: EMD Model: SD 24; Unit 426
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 63, Folder 169)
- Series XXXIV: Washington Terminal Co. Railroad: Washington D.C. Union Station and Potomac Yards
  This series consists of photographs of the Washington Terminal Company's facilities in Washington D.C. These photographs were submitted to the Commission as Employees' Exhibit 38, are referred to by the letter A in testimony, and were taken by Leo R. Anderson. Mr. Anderson was employed as a locomotive fireman by the WATC. The WATC is a corporation created in Washington D.C. to provide support to railroads using Washington's Union Station. It was established in 1901 by the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad and the Pennsylvania Railroad; Amtrak now owns the controlling interest. The photographs in this series document the tracks in and around Washington Union Station, showing the complexity of train movements in the area. The series also documents the Potomac Yards and the car shops at Ivy City.
  - Railway Express Warehouse, Track 4 (Box 53, Folder 134)
    Northbound movement out of Track 4, Express Warehouse showing switch target and fixed signal. To the left are Tracks 3, 2, and 1 express warehouse. This lead out of the warehouse proceeds into a main running track used by inbound and outbound passenger trains.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 134)
  - View from Railway Express Warehouse (Box 53, Folder 135)
    Passenger terminal, electrified. Note overhead wires and close clearances of tracks.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 135)
  - Railway Express Warehouse, Track 4 (Box 53, Folder 136)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 136)
  - Washington DC Union Station, Passenger Terminal (Box 53, Folder 137)
    Passenger terminal, electrified. Note overhead wires and close clearances of tracks. Railway Express warehouse to right of frame.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 137)
  - Washington DC Union Station, Passenger Terminal (Box 53, Folder 138)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 138)
  - West Yard of Washington Terminal Railroad (Box 53, Folder 139)
    Washington DC Union Station, passenger terminal in background
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 139)
  - View from H Bridge in West Yard, Looking South (Box 53, Folder 140)
    H Bridge, southbound, showing West Yard B&O Side Tracks 1 to 9, E Bridge Tracks 12 to 15 inclusive. K interlocking tower in left background. Picture also indicates the large amount of interlocking switches and cross-overs in this area. All movements through this location are governed by K interlocking tower.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 140)
  - Washington DC Union Station, Passenger Terminal (Box 53, Folder 141)
    Shows train movements in and about the K interlocking tower, and H and J bridges. The B&O, PRR, RFP, C&O, and Southern railroads use these facilities for their operation in the terminal area. (similar to A-22a)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 141)
  - Washington DC Union Station, Passenger Terminal (Box 53, Folder 142)
    B&O Unit #1450, EMD E-8-A
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 142)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 53, Folder 196)
    Shows the signals at the right of the locomotive in a slow-clear position. Location is northbound tube with fixed signal in a slow clear position, which is observed by firemen who in return, relays signal indication to enginemen.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 53, Folder 196)
  - Washington Union Station (Box 55, Folder 142)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 55, Folder 142)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 2)
    Proceeding into north and southbound tubes and reverse movement showing signals as observed by firemen located on left side of locomotive. Proceeding southbound on track No. 26, lower level Union Station concourse. Close clearance at points left of track where employees have to work in and about in performance of their duties necessitating the constant look-out by fireman doing the movement of the train.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 3)
    Proceeding southbound on track No. 26, lower level Union Station concourse. Showing signals as observed by firemen located on left side of locomotive. Picture indicates approaching into cross-overs dividing the north and southbound tubes.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level Approaching Fan Chamber (Box 57, Folder 4)
    Picture shows passing fan chamber. Headlight of another locomotive in the southbound tube can only be observed by fireman from his position on left side of locomotive. If the movement had to use the same track, only firemen could pass warning signal to enginemen. Also note close clearance from abutments.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 5)
    Proceeding in reverse movement into tubes, showing signals as observed by firemen located on left side of locomotive. Picture shows indication of next signal being observed only by the firemen. Signal on left side which would govern reverse movement is shown later.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 7)
    Shows track curvature under the Union Station concourse lower level. Proceeding northbound into track which leads to track 29, 28, or 27. Note curvature of track, also signal governing movement beyond the double curve.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 8)
    Northbound picture showing curvature of track, also leads and interlocking switches govern the movement 29, 28 and 27 respectively. To the right of the picture is the walkway where passengers board trains.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 9)
    Shows a reverse movement under the Union Station concourse lower level. Signal on right hand pedestal in stop position. Observation of this signal by firemen on left side of locomotive. Close clearances in and about other tracks. High tension wires carrying 11,000 volts are pictured overhead.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 10)
    Shows a reverse movement in the north and southbound tubes. Southbound movement out of Track 29 with the next signal in stop position and due to the curvature in the track, observation is by firemen on left side of locomotive.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Under the Union Station Concourse Lower Level, North and Southbound Tubes (Box 57, Folder 11)
    Picture shows southward direction Track 26 showing close clearances and passage ways where employees must pass through. Firemen must be on constant look-out to protect employees.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - North End of Car Shop, View to South Showing Tracks 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, and 10 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    Yard switching in this area has many hazardous features. Views obstructed by jacks, wheels, wheelbarrows, small carts and trucks and other items used by repairmen. Observation of obstruction in and about tracks in this area necessitates a constant look-out by the firemen on the left side of the engine for the safety of the employees in and about the shop area.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Shop Area (Box 57, Folder 13)
    Curvature of track and close clearance, constant look-out of firemen is needed to protect the employees working in and around shop area.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Railway Express Warehouse Looking North with Cars in Track 6 to the Right and Cars in Track 5 to the Left (Box 57, Folder 14)
    Engine working this warehouse area is headed north. Fireman's vision from left side of locomotive protects movement of said cars when any obstructions are in and around the car area. Trucks in picture must be cleared to prevent collisions and accidents.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Railway Express Warehouse, Track No. 6 Looking North (Box 57, Folder 15)
    Showing curvature of track, location of switch target, also derail target which is observed from the left side of the locomotive.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Railway Express Warehouse, Track No. 4 Northbound (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Railway Express Warehouse, Track 3 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    The light signal to the left of the pole is positioned low to the ground. In the center of the picture, there is a fixed signal that is in the stop position, governing all southbound movements. To the extreme right is a yard-switching locomotive with one car, proceeding south.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - West Yard, D.C. Union Station (Box 57, Folder 18)
    B&O car with engine being moved on turntable. In the center of the picture toward the bottom is a fixed signal in the stopped position, which the fireman observes on the left side of the engine.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - View from H Bridge in West Yard, Looking South (Box 57, Folder 19)
    Taken from H Bridge, showing the West Yard B&O Side Tracks 1 through 9 and E Bridge Tracks 12 through 15. Along with the K Interlocking Tower photograph, this photo indicates the large amount of interlocking switches and crossovers in this area. All movements through this location are governed by the K interlocking tower.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Industrial Siding, West Yard (Box 57, Folder 20)
    Shows close clearances and track curvature in the industries of the west yard.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - View from H Bridge of Tracks in West Yard (Box 57, Folder 21)
    Shows the intricacies of train movements in the west yard. Notice the many switches and crossovers.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - View from H Bridge of Tracks in West Yard (Box 57, Folder 22)
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - View of West Yard Tracks, Southern Railroad Passenger Car on Right (Box 57, Folder 23)
    Shows train movements in and about the K interlocking tower, as well as H and J bridges. The B&O, PRR, RFP, C&O, and Southern railroads use these facilities for their operation in the terminal area.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - Under New York Avenue Bridge, Looking West (Box 57, Folder 24)
    This shows close clearances and switches which are observed by the fireman and called to the engineman.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 24)
  - View of B&O Main Line Passenger Tracks, Facing South (Box 57, Folder 25)
    Used by the main line B&O passenger trains, cross-over tracks for yard use, with overhead wires. To the left, the tracks are used by the Pennsylvania Railroad inbound and outbound trains. In the upper-middle part of the picture, the signal bridge "L" governs the north and southbound movements.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 25)
  - The Potomac Yards Roundhouse (Box 57, Folder 26)
    The picture is taken looking east with the shop area running north and south.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 26)
  - Potomac Yards, Hump Track (Box 57, Folder 27)
    Picture shown with two yard switches pushing cars over the Hump in a southward movement. View taken from Route 1.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 27)
  - Potomac Yards, Classification Yard and RFP Main Lines (Box 57, Folder 28)
    On the left is a full view of the classification yards. To the right is a southern view of the main lines used by the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad with a fixed position signal in view.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 28)
  - Potomac Yards, Classification Yard and RFP Main Lines (Box 57, Folder 29)
    On the right are the Potomac Yards and hump tracks. To the left are the northbound and southbound main lines used by the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad.
    - Item 1: Click for Image (Box 57, Folder 29)